Guide to the Civic Legislative League Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Civic Legislative League Records
1949-1952.
Civic Legislative League (N.Y.)
8.5 linear ft (in 18 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library,
MS#0228
4078609
This collection contains office files, financial records, printed materials and card files pertaining to the Civic Legislative League, 1949-1952.
Historical Note
The Civic Legislative League (1950-1952) was concerned with securing effective social welfare legislation for New York State.
Scope and Content
Files covering the fields of family welfare, correction, education, health, and housing. Special emphasis is placed on child welfare.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in four series:
Series I: Office Files
Series II: Printed Material
Series III: Financial Records
Series IV: Contact Information
Subjects
Public welfare--Law and legislation--New York (State); Families--New York (State); Family social work--New York (State); Corrections--New York (State); Education--New York (State); Public health--New York (State); Housing--New York (State); Public housing--New York (State); Child welfare--New York (State); Cards files.; Directories.; Financial records.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
M-63-06-18 Citizens Union Gift
Gift of the Citizens Union, 1963.
- Series I: Office Files
  - Office Files (Box 1-8)
    - A - Child Labor - 1950 (Box 1)
      - Albany Dinner (cancelled) (Box 1)
      - Animal Experimentation (Box 1)
      - Annual Meeting - May 25, 1951 (Box 1)
      - Black Market in Babies - 1950-1952 (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Attendance
        - (general) (Box 1)
        - Briefs (Box 1)
        - Clippings, Releases, Memos (Box 1)
        - Meeting - Feb, 16, 1951 (Box 1)
        - Re Passage- of Bureau of Attendance Bill - 1951 (Box 1)
      - Cash Relief (Box 1)
      - Child Labor - 1950 (Box 1)
    - Child Labor - 1951 - Co (Box 2)
      - Child Labor - 1951-1952 (Box 2)
      - Children's Court - 1950-1952 (Box 2)
      - Comments on Miscellaneous Bills (Box 2)
      - Committee on Legislative Report - 1949 (exploratory committee) (Box 2)
      - Corrections & Courts - 1950-1952 (Box 2)
    - D (Box 3)
      - Day Care - 1950-1952 (Box 3)
      - Disclosure of Records - 1951-1952 (Box 3)
      - Discrimination in Housing (Box 3)
    - E - H (Box 4)
      - Executive Committee (by-laws-and minutes) (Box 4)
      - Education Committee (Box 4)
      - Fiscal Independence of School Districts (Box 4)
      - Form letter on New Board Members (Box 4)
      - Formation of the League - 1949-1950 (Box 4)
      - Fund Raising Brochure (Box 4)
      - Fund Raising Manual - September 25, 1951 (Box 4)
      - General Committee Memberships (Box 4)
      - Health Committee (Box 4)
      - Health Education Committee (Box 4)
      - Horan Plan (Box 4)
      - Housing Committee (Box 4)
    - I - Membership (Box 5)
      - Improved Legislative Procedures - 1951-1952 (Box 5)
      - Joel Earnest
        - 1951
          - Legislative Report (Box 5)
          - Legislative History of Civ. Leg. League Bills (Box 5)
        - 1952
          - Legislative Report (Box 5)
      - Land Acquisition Authorities - 1951-1952 (Box 5)
      - League
        - Bylaws (Box 5)
        - Certificate of Incorporation (draft) (Box 5)
        - Letterhead (Box 5)
        - Office Machinery (Box 5)
        - Requests for Information (Box 5)
      - Legislative Action Committee etc. (Box 5)
      - List of 1951 Bills on File (Box 5)
      - Membership
        - 1951 (general) (Box 5)
        - Brochures (Box 5)
        - Invitations, Acceptances etc (Box 5)
        - Meeting
          - April 26, 1950 (Box 5)
          - November 20, 1950 (Rochester) (Box 5)
          - November 1, 1951 (Buffalo) (Box 5)
        - (File) New Advisory Board Members 1950 (Box 5)
        - New Members Board of Directors 1950 (Box 5)
        - Lists (Box 5)
    - Mental Health - Mu (Box 6)
      - Mental Health (Box 6)
      - Mental Hospitals (Box 6)
      - Mentally Retarded Children (Box 6)
      - Migrant Labor (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence with Members - 1949-1952 (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous Legislation, Proposals, etc. (Box 6)
      - Multiple Dwellings - 1950-1951 (Box 6)
    - N - P (Box 7)
      - Narcotics (Box 7)
      - Organisational Data (Box 7)
      - Personnel (Box 7)
      - Prospective Trips (Box 7)
      - President's Report 1950-1951 (Box 7)
      - Permanent Placement of Children in free homes - 1950-1952 (Box 7)
    - R - W (Box 8)
      - Report on League Progress (Box 8)
      - Reports etc. on Trips (Box 8)
      - State Reimbursement - Proposed Changes (Box 8)
      - State Reimbursement to Lodging House (Box 8)
      - Welfare Committee (Box 8)
- Series II: Printed Material
  - Printed Material (Box 9-12)
    - New York State Publications (Box 9)
      - Commission Against Discrimination (Box 9)
      - Commission on Coordination of State Activities (Box 9)
      - Department of Commerce (Box 9)
      - Department of Labor (Box 9)
      - Department of Mental Hygiene (Box 9)
      - Department of Social Welfare (Box 9)
      - Housing Division (Box 10)
      - Special Committee of Social welfare (Box 10)
      - Welfare Conference (Box 10)
      - Copies of New York State Legislature Bills - 1950-1951 (Box 10)
    - Information on Other Organizations (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous Publications (includes misc. publications on correction) (Box 12)
- Series III: Financial Records
  - Financial Records (Box 13-15)
    - Financial Correspondence and Statements (Box 13)
    - Contracts, leases, tax information & expense accounts (Box 13)
    - Bank Statements (Box 14)
    - Cancelled Cheeks (Box 14)
    - Bills paid (Box 14)
    - Checkbooks (Box 15)
    - Bankbooks (Box 15)
    - Ledgers (Box 15)
    - Accountbook (Box 15)
- Series IV: Contact Information
  - Addressograph Plates (Box 16)
  - 4 card files containing names, addresses & phone numbers of individuals and organizations (Box 17-18)